you know to bring back the growth
momentum
for the company in terms of profit
that was about 27 crores so that had
some impact
when you
you know write
so if you see our growth in the month of
march we had a very high goal
or
income
over the next 12 months so that's the
main reason but if you look at the
combined ratio which
adjusts for this
annually in terms
year
the most of the losses came because of
the covet
impact
uh for the industry of the
the industry has paid more than 25 000
covered
claims close to 30 000. we are one
industry which has had this kind of a
hit
and we have not gone to anyone asking
for any support
industry average profits
such as
our combined ratio was very very adverse
because we had very high losses uh
driven by covet uh claims
so that was the main impact for the
whole year
so obviously numbers will improve from
108 in the year you know forward we are
very optimistic about
our business next year
specifically for isis
[Music]
we did the integration with the
bhartiyaksa business that we uh acquired
uh that happened this year bharti aksaka
combined ratio was always elevated so
when we merge the two companies it takes
a bit of time for that to
uh even out we are beginning to see the
benefit play out in terms of business
top line the benefit is already there
the cost we are gradually bringing it
under control but next year we look uh
it looks very very positive in terms of
both growth and uh profiting
so coffee margin here in terms of
capital and if you see
uh you know the dividend that we've
declared it's actually higher than you
know what we've been declaring in the
past
to solve
when the claim happens for a year
we have to take a solvency hit but that
gets ironed out over the next three
years
as i was explaining and i think that
should get evened out in the years
uh
so first nine months the that is correct
we lost a bit of market share in motor
own damage
if you look at ics lombard we were very
strong in private car and to win a new
business new sourcing
uh or
for i sell you know for the whole
industry it has been bad because private
car sales were lower sales were low so
that is the reason why we've lost a bit
of market share plus we are always
focused on building a sustainable
business other market aggression
we are a bit careful so that was the
reason but if you look at this quarter
again we've gone back to our uh you know
growth numbers and in fact in the month
of march we've outgrown the industry
both in motor and
in the month of march yes
what you said in terms of market share
drop was true for the nine months but as
you see this quarter our growth is in
line
so we if you look at the big segment
where we had lot of losses the health
segment because of covet losses uh as a
company in ic silombard we have not
taken a price hike
this year we have taken a small price
like the previous year
after a few years
in the year 2020 we just took a price
hike of about seven eight percent after
seven years for seven years we
maintained prices so uh you know when we
look at price increase we do not look at
one-time events like covet we look at
data over years so as of now from icy
snowboard perspective we don't have any
intention of increasing the retail
uh health insurance premiums going ahead
on the group side we had to take some
increases which which is group is
basically for corporates
and
this is between individual corporates
because it's for it's a contract with
each company so that you know the
increase will be different across
different companies
you know impact on inflation interest
rate
for an unpredictable vehicle in terms of
what that does to indian economy and
every business but if we stay with the
current environment we are very
optimistic uh in terms of growth we have
been investing in adding more
distribution channels we've merged the
two companies that businesses the merger
has gone through really well and we are
very optimistic about our growth and you
know both into the top line and in
profitable for the year
okay uh sir
because we are a foreign company
but global
geopolitics has impact on the global
macro be it in terms of commodity price
inflation
uh be it in terms of interest rate be it
in terms of global liquidity
and if you see for example private car
there is a supply constraint that is
continuing and that has got worsened
because of the ukraine crisis so these
are the impact not that we have exposure
in these countries
[Music]
you